<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrik Eriksson&apos;s Page</title>
    <description>Personal Page of Patrik Eriksson</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4001/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Merry Xmas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Test
Merry Xmas
Merry Xmas
Merry Xmas&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 12:53:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/xmas/2022/12/24/merryxmas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/xmas/2022/12/24/merryxmas/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SyncNote Alpha Dev Release</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce the alpha release of
SyncNote, a simple notes app for Android and PC
which lets you easily synchronize your notes between
your mobile and PC devices. The app is developed
using Jetpack Compose and Jetbrains Compose Desktop
for the JVM release, I used Kotlin Multiplatform to share 
source-code between platforms. I developed this app
during the last few months as a personal exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the source code at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/esp-er/syncnote&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:53:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/syncnote/kotlin/apps/windows/android/linux/2022/08/25/syncnote-alpha/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/syncnote/kotlin/apps/windows/android/linux/2022/08/25/syncnote-alpha/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A new, easier way of improving JVM startup-time using Java 19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dynamic CDS with Java has been available with since JDK version 12. Depending on your program,
enabling it can result in slight startup-time improvement, or as much as &amp;gt; 3x for larger applications.
I recommend always using it in order to improve startup time for all your Java programs.
Enabling dynamic CDS usually involves: first adding a flag in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;java&lt;/code&gt; startup command for
initially creating the archive, use a command such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;java -XX:ArchiveClassesAtExit=archive.jsa -jar yourapp.jar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shared class data archive will be written as archive.jsa in your current directory.
Then, to enable use of CDS, after completing the previous step, you have to supply a different flag in order to use the archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;java -XX:SharedArchiveFile=archive.jsa -jar yourapp.jar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SharedArchiveFile command line argument must be used on all subsequent runs.
After jumping through these hoops you can finally enjoy faster startup times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, there’s more! It seems that using 2 steps in order achieve this functionality would be redundant.
Oracle has thought of us developers and helped to make our lives
slightly easier: starting from Java 19, developers can use a new flag called
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-XX:AutoCreateSharedArchive&lt;/code&gt; together with previously existing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-XX:SharedArchiveFile=&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we can simply run a single command to save us some and effort, the archive
will be created after first run and exit of the application. After the first run,
the archive will be loaded automatically and used during class loading. Just enter both flags in your Java startup command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;java -XX:+AutoCreateSharedArchive -XX:SharedArchiveFile=archive.jsa -jar yourapp.jar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your fast JVM startups using just 1 command!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 23:09:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/jvm/java/apps/dev/2022/07/15/jdk19-appcds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/jvm/java/apps/dev/2022/07/15/jdk19-appcds/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
